Max Perkins discovered Ernest Hemingway and F. Scott
Fitzgerald. But he never met anyone like Thomas Wolfe.
Genius is a history, drama film directed by Michael Grandage.
New York in the 1920s.
Max Perkins, a literary editor is the first to sign such
subsequent literary greats as Ernest Hemingway and F.
Scott Fitzgerald.
When a sprawling, chaotic 1,000-page manuscript by an unknown writer falls into his
hands, Perkins is convinced he has discovered a literary genius.
Max Perkins, played by Colin Firth.
Thomas Wolfe, played by Jude Law.
Aline Bernstein, played by Nicole Kidman.
Louise Saunders, played by Laura Linney.
F. Scott Fitzgerald, played by Guy Pearce.
Ernest Hemingway, played by Dominic West.
Genius is a 2016 biographical drama film directed by Michael Grandage and written by John Logan,
based on the 1978 National Book Award-winner Max Perkins: Editor of Genius by A.
Scott Berg.
The film stars Colin Firth, Jude Law, Nicole Kidman,
Laura Linney, Dominic West, and Guy Pearce.
It was selected to compete for the Golden Bear at the
66th Berlin International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of new york city,
biography, writer, book editor, novelist.
The tone is emotional.